onehowto.com 2019-02-03

# Privacy policy - onehowto.com

## 1\. Application field

Red Link To Media, S.L. (from now on “oneHOWTO”) compromises to respect the privacy of those who visit and use its website, whose main page is found under the address www.onehowto.com (the "Website”).

The current Privacy Policy aims to inform the user on the treatment of personal data that can be gathered through the Website and any associated services, in accordance with Organic Law 15/1999, December 13th, regarding Personal Data Protection, the regulation that it develops and Law 34/2002, July 11th, for Services of the Information Society and Electronic commerce. 

The use of the Website of any of its associated services implies the acceptance on the user's behalf of the contended dispositions in the current Privacy Policies, and that its personal data can be treated according to what is stated on the site. 

## 2\. File responsability

The user's personal data gathered on the Website will be included on a file whose responsibility lies upon oneHOWTO with social address at C/Jordi de Sant Jordi, 11, Bajos - 08027 - Barcelona (Barcelona). % nombre_proyecto% informs the User of the existence of personal data files registered under the GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation), for the fulfillment of legitimate purposes of the entity.

## 3\. Collection of data

We may collect the following information:  
\- IP  
\- Name  
\- contact information including email address  
\- other information relevant to surveys and/or offers for customers.

We will ask your permission to contact you. If you authorize us, we will use your email address to communicate items which may be of interest to you. If you do not wish to receive these communications, you will be given the opportunity to unsubscribe by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of each email.

**What do we do with the information we collect?**

We need this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, for the following reasons in particular:  
\- Internal record keeping.  
\- We may use this information to improve our products and services.  
\- Using the email address you have provided, we may send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information we think you may find interesting.

From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email or phone. We may use the information to customize the website according to your interests. 

## 4\. Unsubscription

The user will be able to choose not to receive commercial communications from oneHOWTO at any given moment through the links established to do so on each email address from oneHOWTO or by contacting the business via email or postal address which is given in section 9 of the present document. 

## 5\. Confidentiality and security

The user's personal data will be treated with total confidentiality. oneHOWTO informs that technical and organizational measures will be adopted to avoid any alteration, loss, treatment or non-authorized access to data, in view of the state of technology, the nature of stored data and the risk of those who are exposed, may it come from human action or physical or natural medium. However, there is not a completely secure system, which is why oneHOWTO cannot guarantee total protection of data at any given moment and under any circumstance external to oneHOWTO. 

## 6\. Third party data

If the user gives personal information of third parties, this party guarantees having obtained previous consent and having been previously informed on the conditions and aim from which oneHOWTO will use his or her personal data. If oneHOWTO requires, the user must credit having obtained such consent. 

## 7\. Underage users

The Website does not intentionally record personal data of users under fourteen (14) years old. 

If a user under fourteen (14) years old gives his or her information, the person will guarantee that he or she has had consent from his or her parents or tutors. If oneHOWTO requires, the user must prove such consent. 

## 8\. Data quality

Data given by the user must be exact and true. In any such case, it is the user's obligation to keep their data updated. 

## 9\. Access, rectification, cancelation and objection rights

The user can contact oneHOWTO at any time to access, modify, cancel or object to any of their personal data by sending an email to info@onehowto.com, or sending a written letter to Red Link To Media, S.L. (Ref.: Data Protection), C/Jordi de Sant Jordi, 11, Bajos - 08027 - Barcelona, Barcelona.

## 10\. Cookies

This Website uses cookies. Cookies are small data files that generate on the user's device and allow the Website to know certain information from the user's activity when browsing and logging in to the site. Cookie files are only linked to an anonymous user and its computer (IP address). These files do not give references that can find out the name and surnames of the user. oneHOWTO will use such information to optimize content, make browsing on the site easier and adapt its services to the user. In any case, the user has the option to block the generation of cookies through the according option on his or her navigation program. However, oneHOWTO informs that disabling cookies can mean a limitation of the functionalities on this Website. 

Moreover, this Website uses third party cookies, including Google, to establish user profiles that allow us to know what your preferences are, as well as to offer advertisements according to previous Website searches made by the user. The user has the option to disable such cookies on http://www.google.com/intl/es/privacy/ads/.

## 11\. Social pluggins

The Website uses social plugins from [Facebook, Twitter, Youtube, Pinterest, Instagram and Google].

Any user who wants to know what data is gathered through such social plugins and know how they are treated, must visit each of the pages' privacy policy. 

## 12\. Spam

oneHOWTO does not approve "spamming". Such term means repeated and systematic message sending from unwanted email addresses, normally with a commercial character, to people to whom the receiver has never kept any contact with, or that has expressed his or her will to stop receiving messages from such address. 

## 13\. Processing data

The company responsible for the processing of data is Red Link to Media SL., whose other identification and communication data you can find at the beginning of this privacy policy.

In compliance with the provisions of the Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data (GDPR), we inform you that the data you provide to us as a registered user will be processed for:

Keep your user profile active on our platform, allowing you to interact and use the different tools that we put at your disposal as a registered user. Your profile will remain active as long as you do not make the corresponding withdrawal of consent.

If you subscribe to one of our portals to automatically receive the news that we publish for them, your email address will be used to send you this news. 

If you participate by writing comments, your username will be published. We will not publish your email address under any circumstances. 

All of your personal data is stored on servers located within the European Union and under specific security measures aimed at preventing unauthorised access or information leakage.

Additionally, the personal data that we collect will be treated confidentially, applying the technical and organisational measures established in our internal security policy; we also inform you that a risk assessment and impact analysis has been carried out to ensure that we protect our users’ information in order to prevent its improper access, manipulation or elimination.

The legal basis for all of the processes listed above is consent; we will keep the necessary information to prove that you gave consent when you registered with us. You may withdraw your consent at any time in your profile or by unsubscribing from your account.

We also inform you that you have the right to access, rectify, oppose, delete and limit the processing of your personal data, and you may exercise this right by writing to the address of the person responsible. We will keep your data as long as you keep your profile active; if you unsubscribe, we will delete your profile and keep your personal data for a period of 3 years in order to be able to respond to any responsibilities arising from the processing of your personal data.

All the contributions (comments) you have made to our portals will be kept, but will be associated with an anonymous username called “User disabled”.

We also inform you of the possibility of filing a complaint with the Spanish Data Protection Agency in the event that you consider that the processing of your data is in adequate. 

In addition, we inform you that you can contact our Data Protection Officer at the following email address: [info@linktomedia.net](mailto:info@linktomedia.net)
